

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · DATA ANALYST · QUANTITATIVE TRADEF

□ (510)875-4012 | ■ LuisMouxDominguez@gmail.com | □ Imoux | □ LuisMouxDominguez

Summary _____

I bring more than a decade of experience in software development with exposure to various industries. I have performed much data analysis in academic research labs (at UPRM, UW-Madison, and Princeton), a Silicon Valley multinational and at a trading firm. I have stepped up to the plate when a firm needed revenue by profitably trading quantitative strategies. I have consistently exceeded expectations as evidenced by a steady stream of bonuses & raises and I can directly trace my results to revenue in the millions.

Experience_

CO-OWNER & CTO

Empresas Moux-Orcasita LLC

San Juan, Puerto Rico

Jan. 2016 - current

• Bootstrapping businesses, creating technology for ventures, and consulting.

Great Bay Global LLC (previously known as Great Bay Energy)

San Juan, Puerto Rico

Jan. 2014 - Mar. 2016

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & PROGRAMMER

• Produced many analysis tools, systems and ETLs for traders that enabled revenue generation.

- Generated profits in the millions (within 6 months) via own and co-managed portfolios (30+, PJM & ERCOT).
- Produced an improved version of an existing trade mining system (410% in time-to-completion, from week to hours).
- Decreased deployment pullbacks by an order of magnitude by introducing agile + lean methodologies & best practices.

OSIsoft, LLC San Leandro, California SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Sep. 2008 - Dec. 2014

- Built the BI project that support management uses to make decisions and improve qualitive of service.
- Contributed to central projects (mPI & Pipeline) that generate millions in revenue and on which the company bets its future.
- Resolved over 1,600 support cases (11th/100s most productive volume-wise, in Spanish & English) across various industries.
- Ran scale tests for the C. Advisory Service's Advanced Metering Infrastructure initiative and improved existing throughput by 25%.

Molecular Thermodynamics lab

Madison, Wisconsin

RESEARCH ASSISTANT / GRADUATE STUDENT

Sep. 2006 - Mar. 2008

• Analyzed phase transitions of liquid crystals via atomistic molecular dynamics and Monte Carlo (own code).

Education

2008 **University of Wisconsin**, MS in Chemical Engineering Madison, WI University of Puerto Rico, BS in Chemical Engineering, certificate in Biotechnology 2006 Mayagüez, PR

Skills & References _____

SKILLS

- Programming: C#, F#, .NET, JavaScript, Python, RabbitMQ, XML, XSLT, Azure (tables, sql), ASP.NET WebApi, ETL, BI
- Databases & Environments: PI System, RabbitMQ, SQL, MongoDB, Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, Linux, SSAS, SSIS, Scrum, Kanban
- Others: Data Warehousing, Threat modeling, Portfolio generation & optimization, Risk management, Updata, Integrations

REFERENCES

Reference 1:	Michael Flaherty	amflaherty@gmail.com	ex co-owner of Great Bay Energy	(617)335-0311
Reference 2:	Daniel Lázaro	kapokasa@gmail.com	colleague at OSIsoft	(510)347-2669
Reference 3:	Steve Nye	steven@osisoft.com	VP Customer Support at OSIsoft	
Reference 4:	Melvin Batista	melbatista@gmail.com	contractor at Great Bay Energy	(787)678-1650
Reference *:	refer to recommendations within LinkedIn profile			